inspiretothrive.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy – Inspire To Thrive

The privacy policy here on Inspire to Thrive has been updated on May 24, 2018.

### Who we are

Our website address is: [https://inspiretothrive.com](https://inspiretothrive.com./)

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form. Additionally, the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. We use the Thrive Comment System here.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself). You may [read more here](https://automattic.com/privacy/) on their privacy policy.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

Our contact forms ask for a name and email address only. This is strictly for our email newsletter which is sent out on an average of once per week. You may opt out of it at any time. We currently use MailChimp as our email provider.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. Then, when you you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google analytics to track our website traffic. Similarly third-party services and advertising partners may collect basic information too. [You can read about their policy here.](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

### Who we share your data with

Third party providers [like Kingged](https://kingged.com/privacy-policy/) with whom you share site data, including partners, cloud-based services, payment processors, and third party service providers, and note what data you share with them and why. Link to their own privacy policies if possible.

Push Engage is another third party we use if you subscribe to push notifications. You can check [Push Engage’s updated policy here.](https://www.pushengage.com/gdpr)

Not to mention, by default WordPress does not share any personal data with anyone.

### How long we retain your data

However if you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically. Hence, instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Similarly, website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. Of course you can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. Finally, this does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. Again, you can check out [Thrive comments policy here.](https://thrivethemes.com/privacy-policy/)

If you sign up for our newsletter it is through Mail Chimp. You can [read Mail Chimp’s own policy here.](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

### Contact information

Contact us at info@InspireToThrive.com

### How we protect your data

Equally important, we use HTTPS here on Inspire to Thrive.

The Hyper Text Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) is the secure version of HTTP. It is the protocol over which data is sent between your browser and the website that you are connected to. The ‘S’ at the end of HTTPS stands for ‘Secure’. It means all communications between your browser and the website are encrypted. Therefore HTTPS is often used to protect highly confidential online transactions. These transactions may include online banking and online shopping order forms.

In addition, web browsers such as Internet Explorer, Firefox and Chrome also display a padlock icon in the address bar to visually indicate that a HTTPS connection is in effect.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

Therefore, If you believe you have had a breach here, contact me immediately at Lisa@InspireToThrive.com

### What third parties we receive data from

In the same fashion, our advertisers receive data once you click on their ads or links throughout this website.

### Industry regulatory disclosure requirements

This Privacy policy has been updated May 24, 2018 for [Inspire to Thrive.](https://inspiretothrive.com/)
